はい、お茶
珂朵莉：给，茶。
Here's your tea.
すまんな、クトリ
威廉：谢了，珂朵莉。
Thanks, Chtholly.
いいえ
珂朵莉：不客气。
You're welcome.
なんかお前、虫の居所でも悪いのか？
威廉：你总觉得，心情不太好吗？
Is something bothering you? You seem in a bad mood.
別に、これっぽっちも、ちっとも機嫌なんて損ねてないですけど
珂朵莉：并没有，我一点、一丁点都没有不高兴。
Not particularly. My mood isn't ruined in the slightest.
ああ、そうか
威廉：啊，这样啊。
Oh, I see.
で、レンはいつまで俺の膝にいるつもりだ？
威廉：话说，奈芙莲你打算在我膝盖上待到什么时候？
And Ren, how long do you plan on staying on my lap?
この本を読み終えるまで
奈芙莲：直到读完这本书。
Until I finish this book.
いい加減、重いんだがな
威廉：说实话，挺沉的啊。
You're getting a bit heavy, you know.
ヴィレムの膝枕だと集中できる
奈芙莲：枕着威廉的膝盖能集中注意力。
I can concentrate better using Willem's lap as a pillow.
それに、体への適度な荷重は安心感をヴィレムに与える
奈芙莲：而且，身体适度的负重能给威廉带来安心感。
Besides, a moderate weight on your body gives you a sense of security.
あ、そうか
威廉：啊，是吗。
Oh, really?
もう！どうして君はすぐにそう何でも納得しちゃうのよ！
珂朵莉：真是的！为什么你总是这么快就接受现实啊！
Jeez! Why do you just accept everything so easily!
保護者として、お前らの意思意見を尊重しただけだろ
威廉：作为监护人，我只是在尊重你们的意愿和意见罢了。
As a guardian, I'm just respecting your thoughts and opinions.
娘たちの言うことは絶対だからな
威廉：毕竟女儿们说的话就是绝对的。
The daughters' word is absolute, after all.
うふふ
艾瑟雅：唔呼呼。
Uhuhuh.
技官は相変わらずっすね
艾瑟雅：技官还是老样子呢。
The technician is the same as ever.
この場合、夫婦漫才って言うより
艾瑟雅：这种情况，比起说是夫妻相声
In this case, rather than a comedy duo...
親子漫才って言った方がいいっすか？
艾瑟雅：不如说是父女相声更合适吧？
...should I call it a father-daughter comedy act?
アイセア！夫婦って別に私は……
珂朵莉：艾瑟雅！什么夫妻，我也没……
Ithea! Married couple? I'm not really...
先輩たち、ここにいたんですね！
缇亚忒：前辈们，原来在这里啊！
Found you, seniors!
ど、どうしたのティアット、そんなに慌てて
珂朵莉：怎么了，缇亚忒，这么慌张。
W-What's wrong, Tiat? Why are you in such a rush?
映画です、映画なんです！
缇亚忒：是电影，是电影啊！
A movie! It's a movie!
映画？
奈芙莲：电影？
A movie?
なんか新作でも見てきたんっすか？
艾瑟雅：是去看了什么新作吗？
Did you go see a new release or something?
ううん、違うの
缇亚忒：不，不是的。
No, that's not it.
私、映画を撮る！
缇亚忒：我要，拍电影！
I'm going to make a movie!
終末なにしてますか？忙しいですか？救ってもらっていいですか？
珂朵莉：末日时在做什么？有没有空？可以来拯救吗？
What do you do at the end of the world? Are you busy? Will you save us?
スペシャルオーディオドラマ
珂朵莉：特别广播剧
Special Audio Drama
「名監督ティアット」
缇亚忒：《名导演缇亚忒》
"Great Director Tiat"
つまり、倉庫の掃除当番だったティアットが
威廉：也就是说，负责仓库打扫的缇亚忒
So, Tiat, who was on warehouse duty...
なぜかたくさん仕舞われていた映像晶石を見つけて
珂朵莉：无意中发现了大量堆放的影像晶石
...somehow found a bunch of stored visual crystals...
ナイグラートに使用許可を求めたところ
奈芙莲：向妮戈兰请求使用许可时
...and when she asked Nygglatho for permission...
あっさりOKが出たってわけっすか
艾瑟雅：她就很干脆地答应了，是吗
...she just gave her the OK, right?
そうなの！
缇亚忒：没错！
Exactly!
映画！ああ、私の大好きな数々の名作
缇亚忒：电影！啊，我心目中那些挚爱的杰作
Movies! Ah, all the masterpieces I love...
「脱皮する隣人に卵の数だけ抱きしめて」
缇亚忒：《在蜕皮的邻居怀里，献上等同卵数的拥抱》
"In the arms of the molting neighbor, as many hugs as there are eggs"
「鱗逆立てるほどの愛」
缇亚忒：《令鳞片倒竖般的爱》
"Scale-bristling Love"
全部、とかげ映画じゃないのか？
威廉：这不都是蜥蜴电影吗？
Aren't they all lizard movies?
私も、誰かを感動させる映画が撮りたいって前から思ってて
缇亚忒：我也一直想着要拍出那种能感动他人的电影
I've always wanted to make a movie that could move someone.
恥ずかしいけど、ずっと温めてきたストーリーもあるの
缇亚忒：虽然难为情，但我也有一个珍藏已久的故事
It's embarrassing, but I have a story I've been refining for a long time.
どんな内容？
奈芙莲：什么内容？
What's it about?
えっとね
缇亚忒：那个嘛
Well...
高貴な身分のお嬢様が、窮屈なお屋敷を抜け出して
缇亚忒：一位身份尊贵的大小姐，逃离了压抑的宅邸
A high-born young lady escapes her stifling mansion...
身分を隠したまま街を散策するの
缇亚忒：隐瞒身份在街上散步
...and explores the town while hiding her identity.
ふんふん
艾瑟雅：嗯嗯。
Mhm.
普段見ない街の風景に驚きながら
缇亚忒：在对平日难见的街景感到惊奇之余
While marveling at the unfamiliar city scenery...
偶然出会った美男子に一目で恋に落ちる
缇亚忒：偶然遇见了一位美男子，对他一见钟情
...she falls in love at first sight with a handsome man she happens to meet.
だけどそれは、実は生き別れのお兄さんだったのよ
缇亚忒：但是，其实那个人是失散多年的亲哥哥
But it turns out, he was actually her long-lost big brother!
そして、男性は死ぬ
缇亚忒：然后，那个男人死了。
And then, the man dies.
いきなりぶっ飛んだな
威廉：剧情突然神展开了啊。
That took a sudden turn.
でも、死んだはずの男と瓜二つの人が現れる
缇亚忒：但是，出现了一个和死掉的男人长得一模一样的人
But then, someone who looks exactly like the dead man appears.
再びお嬢様はその美男子と恋に落ちるの
缇亚忒：大小姐再次和那位美男子坠入爱河
The lady falls in love with that handsome man once again.
お嬢様、顔で選んでる
奈芙莲：大小姐看脸选人。
The lady just picks by looks.
そして、その男も死ぬ
缇亚忒：然后，那个男人也死了。
And then, that man dies, too.
サスペンスなのか？
威廉：这是悬疑剧吗？
Is this a suspense movie?
もう恋なんてしない、そう決めたお嬢様だったんだけど
缇亚忒：虽然大小姐决定再也不谈恋爱了
The lady decides she'll never love again, but...
またまた同じ顔をした美男子がやってくるの
缇亚忒：又来了一个长着同样脸孔的美男子
...yet another handsome man with the same face shows up!
もはや軽いホラーっすね
艾瑟雅：这已经是轻微恐怖片了吧。
This is basically a horror movie now.
ところがそれは、ライバル貴族の息子だった
缇亚忒：结果那个人，是敌对贵族的儿子
However, he turned out to be the son of a rival noble.
恋に落ち、真実の愛を求めた二人は
缇亚忒：坠入爱河、追求真爱的两人
Falling in love and seeking true love, the two of them...
街も身分も捨て、新天地へと旅立っていく
缇亚忒：抛弃了城市和身份，前往新天地旅行
...abandon their status and the city, and set off for a new world.
ざっくりそんなお話！どう？
缇亚忒：大致就是这样的故事！怎么样？
That's the gist of it! What do you think?
ふーん、まあいいんじゃねえか
威廉：哼，感觉还行吧。
Hmm, sounds okay, I guess.
で、でもね、ティアット、映画を撮るって難しいんじゃないの？
珂朵莉：但，但是啊，缇亚忒，拍电影不是很难吗？
Bu, but, Tiat, isn't making a movie difficult?
大丈夫です！
缇亚忒：没问题的！
It'll be fine!
映画を作る映画を見て勉強しました、物の本もたくさん読みました
缇亚忒：我看了拍电影的电影来学习，也读了很多相关书籍
I studied by watching movies about making movies and read plenty of books.
その恋人同士の役は、誰がやるんっすか？
艾瑟雅：那一对恋人的角色，由谁来演呢？
Who's going to play the lovers?
ヴィレムとクトリ先輩にお願いします！
缇亚忒：拜托威廉和珂朵莉前辈了！
I'm asking Willem and Chtholly-senpai!
な、俺と！？
威廉：什，我和！？
What? Me and...?!
わ、私ですって！？
珂朵莉：和，和我！？
M...Me?!
強くて綺麗でかっこいい、クトリ先輩は私のイメージぴったりです
缇亚忒：又强又美又帅气的珂朵莉前辈，正符合我的构想
Strong, beautiful, and cool—Chtholly-senpai is my perfect image.
ヴィレムは……
缇亚忒：威廉的话……
Willem is...
他に男の人いないし、まあ引き立て役ならいいかなって
缇亚忒：反正没有其他男人，作为陪衬应该还可以
...well, there are no other men around, so he'll do as a supporting actor.
つれねえなあ、おい
威廉：太冷淡了吧，喂。
How cold.
そ、そんな急に……できないわよ！
珂朵莉：那、那么突然……我做不到啦！
S-So suddenly... I can't do that!
いいじゃねえか、クトリ
威廉：不是挺好的吗，珂朵莉。
Why not, Chtholly?
ティアットがこんなにやる気になってんだ、子供の夢に水を差したくない
威廉：缇亚忒这么有干劲，我不想扫了孩子的兴。
Tiat is so motivated. I don't want to crush a child's dream.
で、でも、相手は君なのよ！
珂朵莉：但，但是，对手戏是你啊！
Bu, but the co-star is you!
もし本当に映画みたいな……
珂朵莉：如果真的有像电影里那样的……
If there are really scenes like in the movies...
ラブシーンがあったら、あったら、あったら
珂朵莉：爱情戏的话，万一有、万一有、万一有……
...like love scenes, if there are, if there are...
クトリ、よだれ
艾瑟雅：珂朵莉，口水。
Chtholly, you're drooling.
はっ
珂朵莉：哈！
Huh!
はい、ティアット監督、女優さんオッケーみたいっすよ
艾瑟雅：好了，缇亚忒导演，女演员好像OK了哦。
Alright, Director Tiat, it looks like our actress is a go.
待ってよ、まだ私やるなんて……
珂朵莉：等等，我还没说要演……
Wait, I didn't say I'd do it yet...
わあ！ありがとう、クトリ先輩！
缇亚忒：哇！谢谢你，珂朵莉前辈！
Wow! Thank you, Chtholly-senpai!
わあ！ありがとう、クトリ先輩！
缇亚忒：哇！谢谢你，珂朵莉前辈！
Wow! Thank you, Chtholly-senpai!
まあいいわ
珂朵莉：算、算啦。
Fine, whatever.
でも演技なんてできないし、あまり期待しないでよね
珂朵莉：但我可不会演戏，别抱太大期待哦。
But I can't act, so don't expect too much.
うーん、いいお天気、絶好の撮影日和
缇亚忒：嗯，天气真好，绝佳的拍摄日。
Mmm, good weather. A perfect day for filming.
監督、人払いオッケーっす
艾瑟雅：导演，现场清理完毕。
Director, we've cleared the area.
ありがとう、助監督
缇亚忒：谢谢你，副导演。
Thank you, assistant director.
カメラマンの準備は？
缇亚忒：摄影师准备好了吗？
Is the camerawoman ready?
撮影機、準備よし、いつでも行ける
奈芙莲：摄影机准备就绪，随时可以开始。
Camera ready. We're good to go.
おまえら、順応早いなあ、おい
威廉：你们几个，适应得真快啊。
You guys are adapting to this way too fast.
撮影には少し興味があった
奈芙莲：我对摄影稍微有点兴趣。
I had a little interest in cinematography.
あ、そうか
威廉：啊，这样啊。
Oh, I see.
そんで、主演女優はどこ行った？
威廉：那么，主演女演员去哪了？
So, where did our leading lady go?
ちょ、ちょっとねえ、レン、本当にこの格好で撮影するの？
珂朵莉：等、等等啊，莲，真的要穿成这样拍摄吗？
Wait, Ren, are we really filming in this outfit?
お嬢様は使用人になりすましてお屋敷を出たっていう設定
奈芙莲：设定是大小姐伪装成佣人逃出宅邸。
The setting is that the lady escaped the mansion disguised as a servant.
メイド服を着るのは当たり前
奈芙莲：穿女仆装是理所当然的。
It's only natural to wear a maid uniform.
しかもこれ、スカートの丈短すぎない？
珂朵莉：而且这个，裙摆是不是太短了？
Besides, isn't this skirt way too short?
どこにあったのよ、もう
珂朵莉：这到底是从哪找来的啊，真是的。
Where did you even find this? Jeez.
多少はサービスも必要っす
艾瑟雅：多少还是需要一点福利的。
A little fan service is necessary.
ほらほら、技官も何か言ってあげるっす
艾瑟雅：好啦好啦，技官也说点什么。
Come on, technician, say something to her.
お、まあ、似合ってんじゃねえか
威廉：噢，那个，挺适合你的。
Oh, well, it looks good on you.
本当！？
珂朵莉：真的！？
Really?!
ならいいわ！
珂朵莉：那就行！
Then it's fine!
ふん、ちょろいっす
艾瑟雅：哼，真好搞定。
Huh. Too easy.
じゃあ、ヴィレムとクトリ先輩にはそこの恋人達っぽく立ってもらって
缇亚忒：那么，请威廉和珂朵莉前辈像情侣一样站在那里。
Okay, Willem and Chtholly-senpai, stand over there like lovers.
おお、ちょい待てティアット、ざっくりどんな話かは聞いたが
威廉：噢，等等，缇亚忒，虽然听了大意
Whoa, hold on, Tiat. I heard the gist of the story...
台本はどうした？
威廉：但剧本呢？
...but what about the script?
セリフが分からなくちゃどうしようもないぞ
威廉：不知道台词的话根本没法演啊。
I can't do anything if I don't know the lines.
そこは、役者さんの感性にお任せ！
缇亚忒：那个就交给演员们的感性来发挥！
I'll leave that to the actors' intuition!
お、お任せ！？
珂朵莉：发、发挥！？
Intuition?!
監督のイメージだけ伝えて、あとは役者が感じるままに演じる
缇亚忒：我只传达导演的构想，剩下的就由演员凭感觉去演。
I'll just give you my vision, then the actors will perform as they feel.
きっとその方が、より自然な演技になるはずです
缇亚忒：那样一定会展现出更自然的演技。
I'm sure that'll make for a much more natural performance.
しかたねえ、成り行きに任せるとするか
威廉：没办法，就顺其自然吧。
Can't be helped. We'll just wing it.
行くぞ、クトリ
威廉：走吧，珂朵莉。
Let's go, Chtholly.
ちょ、君、本気！？待ってよ！
珂朵莉：等，你、你是认真的！？等等我！
Wait, are you serious?! Wait for me!
それじゃあ、えっと
缇亚忒：那么，那个……
Alright then, um...
シーン3、カット10
缇亚忒：场景3，镜头10。
Scene 3, Cut 10.
なあ監督、よく分からんが順番にやらなくていいもんなのか？
威廉：那个导演，虽然不太懂，但不需要按顺序拍吗？
Hey, Director, I don't really get it, but don't we need to do this in order?
撮れるシーンから撮るのがセオリーなんですから
缇亚忒：从能拍的场景开始拍才是常识。
The rule is to film whatever scenes we can first.
行くよ、よーい、スタート！
缇亚忒：要开始了，预备，开拍！
Here we go. Ready... and action!
ほい、カチンコっと
艾瑟雅：嘿，打板（场记板）。
Clapperboard, check.
待て、待ってください、美しい人
威廉：请等一下，美丽的佳人。
Wait, please wait, beautiful lady.
う、美しい人！？そんなこと急に言われても……
珂朵莉：美、美丽的佳人！？突然被你这么一说……
B-Beautiful lady?! Saying that so suddenly...
カット！
缇亚忒：卡！
Cut!
ダメっすよクトリ、素が出すぎっす
艾瑟雅：不行啊珂朵莉，本性暴露得太明显了。
No good, Chtholly. You're being too much like your usual self.
だって！
珂朵莉：可是！
But...!
もう一度初めから、それではテイク2
缇亚忒：重新开始，接下来是第二次拍摄。
Let's take it from the top. Take 2.
撮影準備よし
奈芙莲：拍摄准备完毕。
Camera ready.
よーい、スタート！
缇亚忒：预备，开拍！
Ready... and action!
カチンコ
艾瑟雅：打板（场记板）。
Clapperboard.
待ってください、そこのお嬢さん、落とし物ですよ
威廉：请等一下，那边的小姐，你掉了东西。
Wait a moment, miss. You dropped this.
まあ、ありがとう、お優しい人
珂朵莉：哎呀，谢谢你，善良的先生。
Oh, thank you. You're very kind.
さっきの曲がり角で、私、何かを落としたのかしら
珂朵莉：在刚才的拐角处，我掉了什么东西吗？
I wonder if I dropped something at the corner back there.
このハンケチさ、そしてもう一つ
威廉：这块手帕，还有另外一样……
This handkerchief... and one more thing.
僕を恋に落としていった
威廉：那就是，你让我掉入了爱河。
You let me drop into love.
ぶっ、くそ
艾瑟雅：噗，该死。
(Snorts) Damn.
歯が浮いてきた
奈芙莲：台词太肉麻了。
My skin is crawling.
そ、それではお礼に、あそこのカフェで休んでいきましょう
珂朵莉：那、那么作为回礼，去那边的咖啡厅休息一下吧。
Th-Then, as a thank you, let's go rest at that cafe over there.
ん？よく見れば君のその格好、どこかに仕えるメイドさんかい？
威廉：嗯？仔细一看你这身打扮，是在哪家当差的女仆吗？
Hmm? Looking closely at your outfit, are you a maid serving somewhere?
ええ、そうですの、ほら、あそこの大きなお屋敷の
珂朵莉：是的，没错，就是那边那座大宅邸里的……
Yes, that's right. You see, that big mansion over there...
そして腕を組み、お店へ行く二人
缇亚忒：然后，两人挽着手走向店里。
And so, the two of them link arms and head to the shop.
その後ろ姿をじっくりなめ回すように
缇亚忒：镜头要像仔细舔舐一般，紧盯着他们的背影。
Keep the camera on their retreating figures, as if tracing them.
了解
奈芙莲：了解。
Roger.
そうそう、そのままピントをぼかしながらカメラを空へパンアップして
缇亚忒：对对，就这样一边模糊焦点，一边将镜头摇向天空。
Right, right. Now blur the focus and pan the camera up to the sky.
はい、オーケー！
缇亚忒：好，OK！
And... cut!
ああ、やれやれ、どうにも緊張するな
威廉：哎呀呀，总觉得有点紧张啊。
Oh, good grief, I'm actually nervous.
ど、どうだった？私の演技
珂朵莉：怎、怎么样？我的演技。
H-How was my acting?
あ？お？うんうん、うん
威廉：啊？哦？嗯嗯，嗯
Uh? Oh? Mmm, mmm
それは…
威廉：这个嘛…
That's...
もう最高です！私の思い描いた通りのお芝居でした
缇亚忒：简直太棒了！完全是我心目中的那种演出。
It was perfect! Just the performance I envisioned.
クトリ先輩は本当に何をやって最高です、ね！アイセア先輩
缇亚忒：珂朵莉前辈无论做什么都是最棒的，对吧！艾瑟雅前辈。
Chtholly-senpai is the best at everything. Right, Ithea-senpai?
まあ、味があるというか、癖になると言うか
艾瑟雅：嘛，挺有味道的，或者说，挺让人上瘾的。
Well, it has flavor... or should I say, it's addictive.
努力している様子はひしひしと伝わってくると言うか
艾瑟雅：努力的样子我也确实深切感受到了。
I can definitely feel the effort coming through.
撮影上は問題なし
奈芙莲：拍摄上没问题。
No issues with the footage.
よし、この勢いで次のシーンに行くわよ！
缇亚忒：好，趁着这股劲，去拍下一幕！
Alright, let's keep this momentum and head to the next scene!
次はここの草原で、二人が戯れるっていうシーンを撮るわ
缇亚忒：接下来，在这里的草原上拍一幕两人嬉戏的场景。
Next, we'll film a scene of the two of them frolicking in this meadow.
うーん、街での初対面からどう繋がっていくんだ？
威廉：嗯……怎么从街上的初次见面衔接过来啊？
Hmm. How does this connect to their first meeting in town?
えっと、それは……
缇亚忒：那个，那是……
Um, well...
大丈夫！編集で何とかするから！
缇亚忒：没关系！后期剪辑会搞定的！
It's fine! I'll fix it in editing!
ふーん
威廉：哼……
Mmm.
それじゃあヴィレムは、クトリ先輩と両手を繋いで楽しそうに輪になって踊って
缇亚忒：那么威廉，请拉着珂朵莉前辈的双手，开心地围成圈跳舞。
Now Willem, hold both of Chtholly-senpai's hands and dance happily in a circle.
ネフレン先輩、カメラは最後空へパンアップでよろしくです
缇亚忒：奈芙莲前辈，最后镜头还是请摇向天空。
Nephren-senpai, please pan the camera up to the sky at the end again.
了解
奈芙莲：了解。
Roger.
それじゃあ、よーい
缇亚忒：那么，预备——
Alright... ready...
て、手を、手を
珂朵莉：手、手、牵手……
H-Hands... holding hands...
監督の言うことは絶対だ、やるぞクトリ
威廉：导演的话就是命令，开始吧珂朵莉。
The director's word is law. Let's do this, Chtholly.
そんな急に、ちょっと待ってったら！
珂朵莉：这么突然，等一下啦！
So sudden! Just wait a second!
アクション！
缇亚忒：开拍！
Action!
あはは、あは、あはは
威廉：啊哈哈，啊哈，啊哈哈……
Ahaha, aha, ahaha!
うふ、うふふふふ
珂朵莉：唔呼，唔呼呼呼呼……
Ufu, ufufufufu!
あはは、あはは、あはははは
威廉：啊哈哈，啊哈哈，啊哈哈哈哈……
Ahaha, ahaha, ahahahaha!
う、ふふふ
珂朵莉：唔，呼呼呼……
U, fufufu!
ほら、俯いてないで顔を上げて笑ってないと、楽しそうにならないだろ
威廉：好啦，别低着头，要把脸抬起来笑，不然看起来不开心。
Look, you have to look up and smile, or it won't look like you're having fun.
そんなこと言われても
珂朵莉：你就算这么说……
Even if you say that...
あはは、はは、はは、はは
威廉：啊哈哈，哈哈，哈哈，哈哈……
Ahaha, haha, haha, haha!
んー
缇亚忒：唔——
Mmm...
どうしたの？監督君？
奈芙莲：怎么了？导演。
What's wrong, Director?
あの雲の形
缇亚忒：那个云的形状。
The shape of those clouds.
雲の形？
艾瑟雅：云的形状？
Cloud shape?
あそこに見えてる雲の形が気に入らない
缇亚忒：我不喜欢那边云的形状。
I don't like the shape of those clouds over there.
ここは幸せの象徴として、ハートの形がいいのに
缇亚忒：这里作为幸福的象征，应该是心形的才对。
It should be heart-shaped as a symbol of happiness.
ストップ、ストップ、雲待ちにするっす
艾瑟雅：停，停，等云。
Stop, stop! We're waiting for clouds.
雲待ち？どういうことだ？
威廉：等云？什么意思？
Waiting for clouds? What does that mean?
監督が雲の形が気に入らないって
奈芙莲：导演说不喜欢云的形状。
The director doesn't like the cloud shapes.
ダグウェポンで何とかならないっすか？
威廉：不能用圣剑想想办法吗？
Can't we do something with a Dug-Weapon?
本気で言ってるの？君
珂朵莉：你是认真的吗？
Are you actually being serious?
なるほど、その手があったっすか
艾瑟雅：原来如此，还有这一招啊。
I see. That's one way to do it.
じゃあ、とくらこのバルガリスでっ、と！
艾瑟雅：那么，看我的瓦尔卡利斯——喝！
Alright then, here goes with my Valgulious! Hah!
いつの間に持ってきてたのよ
珂朵莉：什么时候带过来的啊。
When did you even bring that along?
小道具として
奈芙莲：作为道具
As a prop
これも助監督の務め
艾瑟雅：这也是助导演的职责
This is also the assistant director's duty
行ってくるっす！
艾瑟雅：要上了喵！
Engaging!
どあああっ、たぁ！
艾瑟雅：喝啊——哒！
Hyaaaah—tah!
おおー、雲がハートの形になった！
缇亚忒：噢——云变成心形了！
Whoa, the clouds turned into a heart!
今が絶好の撮影チャンス
缇亚忒：现在是绝佳的拍摄时机。
Now's our perfect chance!
撮影機、準備完了
奈芙莲：摄影机，准备就绪。
Camera ready.
よし、やるぞクトリ
威廉：好，开始吧珂朵莉。
Alright, let's do this, Chtholly.
わ、わかったわよ
珂朵莉：知，知道啦。
Got, got it.
う、うふふ、ふふ
威廉：唔，唔呼呼，呼呼……
U, Ufufu, fufu!
あ、あはは
珂朵莉：啊，啊哈哈
Ah, Ahaha
うふふ、ふふふ、うふふ
威廉：唔呼呼，呼呼呼，唔呼呼……
Ufufu, fufufu, ufufu!
あ、はははは
珂朵莉：啊，哈哈哈哈……
Ah, hahahaha
お空の上から、ただいまーっす！
艾瑟雅：我从天空上回来啦——！
Back from the skies!
そして、華麗に着地！
艾瑟雅：然后，华丽着陆！
And a graceful landing!
したっ
艾瑟雅：嘿。
Hah!
やだっ、風が……
珂朵莉：讨厌，风好大……
Oh no, the wind...
ああっ
珂朵莉：啊！
Ah!
は、クトリ先輩の、パ、パ、パ、パン
缇亚忒：哈，珂朵莉前辈的，内、内、内、内……
Ah! Chtholly-senpai's p-p-p-pan...
アりゃりゃ、今の風でチラっちゃったっすか？
艾瑟雅：哎呀呀，被刚才的风吹得露出来了？
Oops, did that wind show a little too much?
いたずらな風の妖精
奈芙莲：恶作剧的风之妖精。
Mischievous wind fairies.
見た！？
珂朵莉：看到了！？
Did you see?!
いえ、何も
威廉：没，什么都没……
No, nothing.
ねえ、今見たでしょ！絶対見えてた！スカートの中見えちゃったでしょ！
珂朵莉：呐，刚才看到了对吧！绝对看到了！裙子里全被看到了对吧！
Hey, you saw just now, didn't you?! You definitely saw! You saw up my skirt!
いやいや、全く視界に
威廉：没有没有，完全没进我的视线。
No, no, it wasn't in my field of vision at all.
ばっちり撮れてる
奈芙莲：拍得一清二楚。
I got it perfectly on film.
ふう、ぎゃあああああ！！
珂朵莉：呜呜，呀啊啊啊啊啊！！
Uhuuu... Gyaaaaaah!!
大丈夫ですよ、クトリ先輩、さすがに今のは
缇亚忒：没关系的，珂朵莉前辈，刚才那段应该
It's fine, Chtholly-senpai. We surely...
使えないでしょう？
珂朵莉：没法用吧？
Can't use that part?
ええ
缇亚忒：嗯。
Yeah.
エンドロールのNG集のところにしか
缇亚忒：顶多只能用在片尾的花絮集里。
Only in the blooper reel during the credits.
使わないで！
珂朵莉：别用啊！
Don't use it!
まあ、クトリのパンツの色が気になる諸兄は、映画の最後の最後まで
艾瑟雅：嘛，在意珂朵莉内裤颜色的诸位，请务必看到电影的最后。
Well, to all you gentlemen curious about Chtholly's panties, watch until the very end.
席を立たずに見てもらうと
艾瑟雅：请不要离席，一直看到最后。
Don't leave your seat until it's over...
見なくていい！
珂朵莉：不准看！
You don't have to watch!
じゃあ次のシーン、水の上を走って、クトリ先輩の乗ったボートを追いかけるヴィレム
缇亚忒：那下一幕，威廉在水面上奔跑，追逐珂朵莉前辈坐的小船。
Next scene! Willem running across the water to chase Chtholly-senpai's boat.
うおおおお！！
威廉：噢噢噢噢！！
Uoooooh!!
すごい、技官が水の上を！
艾瑟雅：厉害，技官居然在水上跑！
Amazing, the technician is running on water!
ああああああああああ！
威廉：啊啊啊啊啊啊啊啊！
Ahhhhhhhhhhh!
あ、沈んだ
奈芙莲：啊，沉了。
Ah, he sank.
クトリ先輩が悪い奴らに絡まれているの
缇亚忒：这一幕是威廉飒爽登场
A scene, where Willem gallantly
颯爽とヴィレムがやっつけるシーン
缇亚忒：打败纠缠珂朵莉前辈的坏蛋
defeats the thugs bothering Chtholly-senpai
アクション！
缇亚忒：开拍！
Action!
よーよー、姉ちゃん、まぶいっすね
艾瑟雅：哟哟，小姐，长得挺正嘛
Yo, yo, baby, you're lookin' good.
ちょっと俺たちと遊んでいかっす
艾瑟雅：跟哥几个去玩会儿
Why don't you hang out with us for a bit?
あ、あれー、誰か助けてー
珂朵莉：啊、啊嘞——谁来救救我——
H-Help! Somebody save me!
待てい！
威廉：住手！
Halt!
な、何者っすか？
艾瑟雅：你、你是谁啊？
Wh-Who are you?
貴様ら悪党に名乗る名前はない！とぉ！
威廉：我没名字要报给你们这些恶党！喝！
I have no name for scum like you! Yah!
どはっ！
威廉：呜哇！
Ugh!
お、覚えてやがれっす、べーっ
艾瑟雅：你、你给我记住了，略——
Y-You'll regret this! Blehh!
おとといきやがれ
威廉：滚远点。
Don't come back.
本当にこんな感じでいいの？
珂朵莉：真的这样演就行吗？
Is it really okay like this?
はいヴィレム、そこで死んで！
缇亚忒：好，威廉，在那儿死掉！
Okay, Willem! Die right there!
痛っ！これ、マジで痛い！
威廉：痛！这个，是真的痛！
Ow! That actually hurt!
はい、そこでクトリ先輩、感激のあまり卵を産む
缇亚忒：好，接下来珂朵莉前辈，因为太感激了，请生个蛋。
Okay, Chtholly-senpai, you're so moved that you lay an egg!
できないわよ！
珂朵莉：办不到啦！
I can't do that!
最後は妖精倉庫で撮影
奈芙莲：最后在妖精仓库拍摄。
The final shot is in the fairy warehouse.
うん。追っ手から逃げてきた二人は、何やかんやあって
缇亚忒：嗯。逃离追兵的两人，经过一番曲折
Yes. The two, fleeing their pursuers
田舎の寄宿舎にやってくる
缇亚忒：来到了乡下的宿舍
eventually arrive at a countryside dormitory.
そして何やかんやあって、二人は愛を誓う、感動的クライマックス
缇亚忒：然后又经过了一番曲折，两人誓约相爱，感动的最高潮！
And after some more stuff happens, they pledge their love. The moving climax!
あー、念のため聞くが、どういった経緯でここに来るかとかは？
威廉：啊，保险起见问一下，到底是怎么个曲折法来到这里的？
Uh, just to be sure, how exactly did they end up here?
大丈夫！編集で何とかするから！
缇亚忒：没关系！后期剪辑会搞定的！
It's fine! I'll fix it in editing!
監督、そこの木の下のあたり、木漏れ日がいい感じ
奈芙莲：导演，那棵树下附近，斑驳的阳光树影感觉很棒。
Director, the sunlight through the leaves by that tree is nice.
おおー、確かに！それじゃあキスシーンはそこで撮りましょう！
缇亚忒：噢——确实！那接吻镜头就在那儿拍吧！
Oh, you're right! Let's film the kiss scene there, then!
き、き、き、き、き、キスシーン！？
珂朵莉：接、接、接、接、接、接吻镜头！？
A k-k-k-k-kiss scene?!
ここまで来たんだ、やるしかねえだろう
威廉：都走到这一步了，只能演了吧。
We've come this far. We have to do it.
ちょ、まっ、引っ張らないで！
珂朵莉：等、等一下，别拉我！
Wait, don't pull me!
は？
珂朵莉：啊？
Uhh?
いい、すごくいい！
缇亚忒：好，非常棒！
Nice, very nice!
木の幹を背にするクトリ先輩にぐっと迫るヴィレム
缇亚忒：威廉逼近背靠树干的珂朵莉前辈
Willem closes in on Chtholly-senpai against the tree.
腕をドンと木に押し付けて
缇亚忒：把手“咚”地撑在树上！
Pressing the arm against the trunk!
は
缇亚忒：啊
Ah
ネフレン先輩、カメラは？
缇亚忒：奈芙莲前辈，镜头呢？
Nephren-senpai, the camera?
大丈夫、既に撮影してる
奈芙莲：没问题，已经在拍了。
It's fine. I'm already rolling.
技官も技官で、やるときはやるっすね
艾瑟雅：技官就是技官，该出手时就出手呢。
The technician really delivers when it counts.
そこでヴィレムが包み込むように、クトリ先輩にき、き、き、キスを！
缇亚忒：威廉顺势抱住珂朵莉前辈，接、接、接、接吻！
Now Willem, embrace her and k-k-k-kiss her!
いいな？クトリ
威廉：可以吗？珂朵莉。
Here I go, Chtholly?
待ってったら！冗談なら怒るわよ！
珂朵莉：就叫你等一下！要是开玩笑的我可要生气了！
I said wait! If this is a joke, I'm going to be mad!
冗談でこんなことするか？
威廉：开玩笑会做这种事吗？
Would I do this as a joke?
え？
珂朵莉：诶？
Eh?
真似事撮影とは言え、ここまでティアットに付き合ってやったんだ
威廉：虽说是模拟拍摄，但既然已经陪着缇亚忒闹到这步了
Even if it's just a mock filming, we've gone along with Tiat this far.
最後まで面倒見るのが、俺らの務めってもんだろう
威廉：照顾她到最后，也是我们的职责吧。
It's our duty to see it through to the end.
いやいやいや、でも、だからって
珂朵莉：不不不，但是，就算那样……
No, no, no, but still...
この角度なら腕で隠せる、本当にする必要はねえよ、安心しな
威廉：这个角度能用手臂挡住，不需要真的做，放心吧。
I can hide it with my arm at this angle. No need to actually do it. Don't worry.
そんなこと言われても、こんなに君の顔が
珂朵莉：就算你这么说，你的脸也离得太……
Even if you say that, your face is so...
近いじゃ……
珂朵莉：太近了……
...so close...
息も、かかって……
珂朵莉：呼吸都，感觉到了……
I can even feel your breath...
クトリ
威廉：珂朵莉。
Chtholly.
ふん
珂朵莉：嗯……
Mmm...
も…駄目
珂朵莉：已经…不行了
I'm... lost
なっ、おい、クトリ！
威廉：那、喂，珂朵莉！
Wh- Hey, Chtholly!
先輩！
缇亚忒：前辈！
Senpai!
きゅう
珂朵莉：（昏过去的声音）
(Faints)
クトリ先輩！クトリ先輩！
缇亚忒：珂朵莉前辈！珂朵莉前辈！
Chtholly-senpai! Chtholly-senpai!
えー、コホン、本日は私の初監督作品
缇亚忒：咳咳。今天，我的第一部导演作品
Ahem. Today, my directorial debut...
「さらば愛しき恋人、恋に恋して愛してるの」完成披露試写会にお集まりいただき
缇亚忒：《再见了亲爱的恋人，恋爱中爱着你》完成发布会，感谢各位的到来。
...the premiere of "Farewell, Beloved Lover: Loving the Love of Loving You"... thank you all for coming.
まことにありがとうございます
缇亚忒：真的非常感谢。
Thank you so very much.
そんなタイトルだったんっすね
艾瑟雅：原来是这样的标题啊。
So that was the title.
言葉の意味、すごく被ってる
奈芙莲：词义，重复得好厉害。
The words are so redundant.
関係者様だけを集めたこの席で
缇亚忒：在只有内部人员的这里
In this private screening for staff
いち早くフィルムをご覧いただければと思います
缇亚忒：希望能让大家尽早看到影片
I hope you enjoy the film early.
関係者も何も
威廉：什么内部人员
"Staff"?
自分たちで撮影して自分たちで見ているだけだよね
珂朵莉：不就是我们自己拍自己看吗
We're just watching what we filmed ourselves.
それでは上映いたします、最後までごゆっくりどうぞ
缇亚忒：那么现在开始放映，请慢慢欣赏到最后。
Now, the screening will begin. Please enjoy it to the end.
でも、あんだけめちゃくちゃなシーンの羅列
艾瑟雅：不过，排了那么多乱七八糟的场景
But with those disjointed scenes
まとまってるんっすかね
艾瑟雅：能成片吗？
I wonder if it even makes sense.
うーん、どうかな
珂朵莉：唔，谁知道呢。
Hmm, I wonder.
レンはどう思う？
珂朵莉：莲觉得呢？
What do you think, Ren?
私はただ撮影してただけ
奈芙莲：我只是负责拍摄而已。
I was just the camera operator.
まあ結果はお察しだろうけどよ
威廉：虽然结果已经能猜到了吧。
Well, we can probably guess the result.
ティアットのやつ、一生懸命やってたんだ、ちょっと見て拍手してやろうぜ
威廉：缇亚忒那家伙可是很努力的，看完给她鼓个掌吧。
Tiat worked hard on it. Let's just watch and give her some applause.
うん、そうよね、面白かったって言ってあげましょう
珂朵莉：嗯，是啊，就跟她说很好看吧。
Yeah. Right. Let's tell her it is interesting.
おっ、始まるっす
艾瑟雅：哦，开始了。
Oh, it's starting.
う、う、うん？
珂朵莉：呃，呃，嗯？
Wh, Wh, What?
どういうこと？
奈芙莲：这是什么意思？
What is this?
何なんっすか、これ
艾瑟雅：这是什么东西啊。
What on earth is this?
そんな、こいつは……
威廉：竟然，这家伙……
No way, this is...
面白い！
：太有趣了！
...Hilarious!
えっへん！
缇亚忒：嗯哼！
Ahem!